## Ashish Yadav

#### FrontEnd Developer

Adaptable professional with 4.5+ years of experience and proven knowledge of capital projects, process development, and improvement. Creating solutions with NGA for the retial legacy systems. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the Modern Web Developer role.



- yadav.ashish233@gmail.com
- Gurugram, india
- in linkedin.com/in/ashishy4

- 7397367544
- ashu1610.github.io/
- github.com/ashu1610

### **EDUCATION**

#### B.Tech (ME)

Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal

06/2013 - 05/2017

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Frontend Developer TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

04/2021 - Present

Client: Citi Bank

- Converting legacy green screen into modern web development using React and Angular framework.
- Calling post microservice with json request and display response on the screen.
- Creating Zconnect API to interact between mainframe legacy system and microservice.
- Developing website maps, application models, API calls, or web pages to meet project goals, user needs, and industry standards.
- Identify problem uncovered by tester and correct problems or refer problem to appropriate personals for correction.
- Maintain understanding of current web technologies or programing practices through continuing education, reading, or participation in professional conferences, workshops and groups.

# Software Developer TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

08/2017 - 03/2021

Client : Westpac Bank, Citi Bank

- Create a new zConnect API and CICS module for NGA.
- Create a new card system for the minors keeping their parents as primary holders.
- Develop online screen, other features, and cost-saving processes like refining queries for leading bank customers in mainframe z/os.
- Work in spirit to deliver the project into production every quarter.
- Developing mainframe module to meet new enhancements into existing functionalities.
- Create change request, package, plan, and new transaction ID as per the project requirement.

## **SKILLS**

React Angular Bootstrap CSS HTML5

Mainframe Python Agile Methodologies

Articulation Data science

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### Online Book Store

 Users can log in, add the book to the cart, view the cart, and check the total bill. created using react - routing, useState, UseEffect, props, Hooks

#### To-do Application

Created todo list application using hooks and usestate from react.

#### Weather Application

 Created weather application using open weather API call in react framework.

#### Pizza Website

responsive pizza restaurant website using routing/switch in react.

#### Travel Website

responsive travel website using routing and switch in react.

#### Agency Website

• created responsive website using bootstrap, css and HTML5.

## **CERTIFICATES**

Certified Frontend Developer using React - IT Training Classes

Agile Way Of Working, Retail Banking and Art Of Articulation - Tata consultancy services training

Certified Machine learning and Data science -AnalytixLabs

## **LANGUAGES**

English Native or Bilingual Proficiency Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Music

Coding

**Next Generation Technologies**